export const questions = [
    {
      id: 1,
      question: "What does the term girl rights on health primarily encompass?",
      options: ["Access to education", "Access to quality healthcare services", "Right to vote", "Right to own property"],
      correctAnswer: "Access to quality healthcare services"
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question: "Which of the following is a significant challenge affecting girls' access to healthcare in many parts of the world??",
      options: ["Overabundance of healthcare facilities", "Gender equality", " Lack of trained healthcare professionals", "Excessive government funding"],
      correctAnswer: "Lack of trained healthcare professionals"
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question: "What is one potential consequence of denying girls access to adequate healthcare services?",
      options: ["Improved community health outcomes", "Enhanced economic development", "Increased maternal mortality rates", "Decreased gender disparity"],
      correctAnswer: "Increased maternal mortality rates"
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question: "Which of the following is a key aspect of ensuring girls' rights on health?",
      options: ["Implementing policies that prioritize boys' health", "Providing comprehensive sex education", "Limiting access to healthcare based on gender", "Excluding girls from healthcare decision-making processes"],
      correctAnswer: "Providing comprehensive sex education"
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question: "What is one strategy to improve girls' access to healthcare in rural areas?",
      options: ["Establishing more urban healthcare facilities", "Providing mobile healthcare clinics", "Increasing healthcare costs", "Limiting healthcare services exclusively to boys"],
      correctAnswer: "Providing mobile healthcare clinics"
    },
    {
      id: 6,
      question: "Which of the following is an example of a reproductive health issue that disproportionately affects girls?",
      options: ["Prostate cancer", "Breast cancer", "Ovarian cancer", "Testicular cancer"],
      correctAnswer: "Ovarian cancer"
    },
    {
      id: 7,
      question: "Why is it essential to address girls' rights on health within the broader framework of human rights?",
      options: ["To perpetuate gender inequality", "To ensure equitable access to healthcare", "To limit girls' opportunities", "To discourage community involvement in healthcare"],
      correctAnswer: "To ensure equitable access to healthcare"
    },
    {
      id: 8,
      question: "In many cultures, what societal factors can hinder girls' access to healthcare?",
      options: ["Gender discrimination", " Equal opportunities", "Empowerment programs", "Gender-neutral healthcare policies"],
      correctAnswer: "Gender discrimination"
    },
    {
      id: 9,
      question: "Which of the following is a fundamental principle underlying girls' rights on health?",
      options: ["Exclusion from healthcare decision-making", "Access to safe drinking water", " Denial of reproductive rights", "Equity and nondiscrimination"],
      correctAnswer: "Equity and nondiscrimination"
    },
    {
      id: 10,
      question: "What role can education play in promoting girls' rights on health?",
      options: ["Reinforcing gender stereotypes", "Limiting access to healthcare", "Empowering girls to make informed health choices", "Decreasing awareness about health issues"],
      correctAnswer: "Empowering girls to make informed health choices"
    },
  ];